MITCHELL R. DORSEY

5793 Opengate Court Cincinnati, OH 45247 (513) 203-3344 -- <u>Email</u> -- <u>LinkedIn</u>

Professional Summary

Junior developer searching for a role that allows me to use my adaptability and communication skills. Constantly yearning to broaden my skill set both technologically and mentally. Past work experiences have given me strengths in thinking on my feet and continuously being flexible. I am choosing a career as a programmer because I enjoy collaborating and contributing to a whole.

Technical Skills

Object Oriented Programming(OOP) - C#, .NET framework **Development Tools and Techniques** - unit testing, integration testing, TDD, Git

Education

Tech Elevator - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2018 - Present

14-week .NET coding bootcamp learning database programming, .NET frameworks and design patterns, web application security, server side programming and client side web programming (Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Web services, JSON, XML)

Cincinnati State - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2017 - May 2018

Studied Electrical Engineering Technology including learning to operate Digital Multimeter(DMM) tool to read volts, amps and resistance of electrical current

University of Cincinnati - Cincinnati, Ohio

September 2013 - December 2014

Studied Finance, pre-Engineering courses and Interpersonal Communication

Technical Experience

Vending Machine Software

• Developed in C# using Object Oriented Programming(OOP) and file.io

Professional Experience

Lynch Imports - Sunman, Indiana

April 2016 - Present

Inventory Specialist

- Continuously learning a variety of new technical and mechanical skills
- Apply practical reasoning and critical thinking with team members to determine course of action for inventory consolidation across many storage locations
- Factor numerous industry regulations into decision making on a daily basis
- Received recognition by name from multiple customers regarding carrying positivity and valuing customers' time

Colerain Fire Department - Cincinnati, Ohio

June 2014 - August 2014

Fire Hydrant Servicer

- Thoroughly logged information and recorded concise, informative comments where necessary
- Carefully inspected company vehicle biweekly noting any irregularities

King's Island Amusement Park - Mason, Ohio

March 2010 - August 2012

Admissions Associate

- Earned exceptional marks in each end-of-summer evaluation, notably organizational skills
- Accurately counted and transacted over \$10,000 in sales daily
- Consistently kept a level head during fast-paced, high stress situations